Of the world of spirits,
in order to celebrate the birthday of the demon king,
they use their blood and change it to a Bloody Parrot
If you have the luck to meet it,
it'll offer you three wishes
to fulfill whatever you want
有一年
Once Prince of Dian is
滇王府预备朝贡
preparing to pay tribute to the imperial court
当今天子的十三箱珠宝
The thirteen caskets of treasures to the king
在一夜间突然失踪
all disappeared within one night
王爷闻讯，焦虑万分
The Prince is perturbed at the news
下令总管郭繁彻夜搜查
and decreed Chief Guo Fan to search at once
当你见到我，就会得到三个愿望
When you see me you'll get 3 wishes;
只要活着，你的愿望就会实现
and as long as you live your wishes will come true
你真的有灵就替我…
If you are that good then...
替我找回王府失窃的十三箱珠宝
then help me retrieve the 13 cases of lost treasures
血鹦鹉果然将王府所失的
The Bloody Parrot has indeed
十三箱珍宝都找回
recovered the lost treasures
实现了郭总管的第一个愿望
and fulfilled chief Guo's first wish
失去的珠宝都找回来了
The lost treasures have been found
不好啦，郭公子坠马死了
Bad news, master Guo died from falling off his horse
儿子…
Son...
我要你把我儿子的命还给我
Give me back my son
把我儿子的命还给我
"The grave of my beloved son, Guo Jia Zhong"
你真的相信这种事
You really believe in such rumors?
你真的相信一只鹦鹉
You really believe a parrot
能使你的儿子复活
could bring your son back to life?
宝库失窃，卑职的责任最大
I am highly responsible for the lost treasures
嫌疑也最大
and suffer the greatest suspicion too
现在失窃的珠宝已寻回
The lost treasures have now been retrieved
犬子是否能复活都已经不重要了
it doesn't matter whether my son can come alive
我相信你的忠心
I believe in your loyalty
也希望你的儿子能够复生
and also hope your son could be brought back to life
可是，啊…
But...
你不要放他出来
Don't let him out
你不能放他出来
You can't let him out
他已经死了，已经变成鬼了
He's dead, he's a ghost now
儿子复活了，我儿子复活了
My son's come back to life
你简直是疯了你
You must be mad
珠宝不见了…
The jewelry is gone...
自从滇王府那批珠宝失踪后
Since those jewelry disappeared
本来已经平静多年的江湖
what might have been a tranquil time
从此也就骚动起来
became a tumultuous period
为了这批价值连城的珠宝
To lay their hands on this treasure
各门各派都在追查血鹦鹉的真相
martial artists tried to track down the Bloody Parrot
他们因为互相猜忌而导致残杀
They killed each other for this
由于残杀而引起仇恨
and hatred was generated
更因仇恨而又互相杀戮
Then hatred gave rise to more killings
可是血鹦鹉的秘密和珠宝的下落
However the Bloody Parrot and the treasure
却始终是一个谜
remained a mystery
你是什么人？为什么要杀我？说
Who are you? Why do you want to kill me?
滇王府的珠宝
The Jewellery of the Prince of Dian
江湖上的人都说是…是你…
Everybody says it's you... it's you
"Dian border"
"Dian House"
你是鬼还是人
Are you a ghost or a man?
我是个将死的人，还没有变成鬼
I am the one who's about to die and as yet not a ghost
是谁害你的
Who harmed you?
是你…
It's you...
我怎么害你的？我自己都不知道
Me? I don't know that
你刚才看见什么
What did you see just now?
一道红光，在这边闪耀着
A streak of red light, shimmering over here
你知道那是什么
Do you know what that is?
不知道
No
你当然不知道
Of course you don't
因为那红光一出现
When that red light appears,
血鹦鹉很快就出现了
the Bloody Parrot will soon appear as well
这只不过是传说而已
It's just a rumour
不，有人看见
No, someone has seen it happen
谁？
Who?
郭繁
Guo Fan
就是滇王府一夜之间
Is he the Chief of the residence of the Prince of Dian
失去那批珠宝的郭总管
who lost all the jewellery in a night?
是
That's him
那么那批珠宝到哪里去了？
Where's all the jewellery?
你赶快离开这里
You'd better hurry and leave
血鹦鹉它…
the Bloody Parrot...
那批珠宝到哪儿去了？
Where's all the jewellery?
血鹦鹉
The Bloody Parrot
血鹦鹉？
The Bloody Parrot?
你是谁？
Who are you?
铁恨
Tie Hen
中原名捕铁手无情铁恨就是你
Are you the famous constable Tie Hen the Merciless?
不错
That's me
你来找谁？
Who are you looking for?
郭简
Guo Kan
找他干什么？
What for?
他是郭繁的兄弟，郭家唯一的活口
He's Guo Fan's brother, the family's only survivor
只有他才能告诉我
Only he can tell me
滇王府失窃那批珠宝的下落
where the lost jewellery of the Prince of Dian is
可惜你来迟了
But you're late
什么
What?
死因你找出来没有
Have you found out the cause of his death?
他是被毒死的
He was poisoned
你看我叶霆风像个下毒的人吗
Do I look like someone who uses poison?
我相信你不会
I don't think you would, but that's because
因为他还没有说出那批珠宝的下落
he hadn't told you the whereabouts of the treasure
如果他说了你以为我就会下毒
Do you think I'd use poison if he had?
很难说
Difficult to say
他临死之前究竟还说了些什么
What did he say before he died?
我为什么要告诉你
Why should I tell you?
因为只有我才能证明你没有下毒
Because, only I can prove your innocence
他说出了三个字
He uttered 3 words
什么字
What?
血鹦鹉
The Bloody Parrot
The Bloody Parrot?
我绝不相信血鹦鹉这种事
I don't believe in such a rumor
我只相信天网恢恢，疏而不漏
I only believe that nothing escapes justice
剖开
Cut it open
你是识货的人
You know your stuff,
应该看得出这是什么
you should know what this is
这是避毒珠，专克五毒
This is an anti-poison pellet
这也是王府失窃的珠宝
and it is also the lost jewelry
他身上既然有避毒珠
Since he kept it
怎么会中毒而死
how could he have died of poison?
有些毒走经脉血管
Some poisons run in the arteries
有些毒走六月府五脏
some in the organs;
本来就不相干
they don't interfere with each other
这件案子另有主谋
There's someone behind this case
他是被人灭口的
His murder was to silence him
主言某人会是谁？
Who is the mastermind?
其实只要找到一样东西
In fact if we could find one thing
这件案子你想不破都不行
you could easily solve the case
找什么？
What is that?
鹦鹉，血鹦鹉
The Bloody Parrot
血鹦鹉？
The Bloody Parrot?
这个东西走得真快，真邪门
It runs away so quickly
就算你追上了，是祸是福也很难说
Even if you caught up with it, it may not be a blessing
祸福由天、生死由命
Fate and death are out of our control
我了解你的心情
I understand how you feel
自你进入了六扇门
Since you entered the cult of the Six Fans
死在你手下的不下有七八十人
70 to 80 people have died at your hands
我从来没有枉杀一个人
I have never killed anyone unjustifiably
可是你杀的毕竟是活生生的人
Nevertheless, you have killed
你双手沾满了血腥
and your hands are tainted with blood
想洗你也洗不干净了
You can't wash off your responsibility
我真是不明白你究竟想说些什么
I can't figure out what you are trying to say
血鹦鹉
The Bloody Parrot
要是你还把我当作朋友
If you still regard me as your friend
叶兄，请把我的尸体运回边寨
please send my body back to the border
"Spirtual Tablet of Tie Hen"
铁捕头是怎么死的
How did constable Tie die?
中毒
He was poisoned
中什么毒
What poison did he die of?
不知道
I don't know
难道连老先生都查不出
Even you can't figure it out?
只要是人杀了他
As long as the murderer is a human being
无论用什么方法我都能查出
I could use whatever means to figure it out
难道凶手不是人
So the murderer is not human?
绝不是
No
客倌，里边请
Sir, inside please
好
Thanks
哎，你看
Look
这里是酒店还是棺村c
Is this a tavern or a coffin shop?
小店只卖酒不卖棺村
We only sell wine, not coffins
那怎么会有棺村？
So why is there a coffin here?
这是那位客倌带来的
That gentleman brought it here
而且他一定要放在这里
and insisted on putting it here
这杯酒轮到我，我干了
My turn to toast
喂，里面有什么
Hey, what's inside?
我跟你说话
I'm talking to you
里边是我朋友
My friend is in there
是死朋友还是活朋友
Is he dead or alive?
只要是朋友，死活都是朋友
Doesn't matter, he is still my friend
死人还会喝酒
Do dead people drink?
现在轮到你干了，我替你喝了
It's your turn, I'll drink for you
这人是疯子，你看怎么样
He's nuts, what do you think?
把他踢出去
Kick him out
我这个朋友活着的时候就喜欢踢人
When my friend was alive he liked kicking people
从来没有被人踢过
He was never kicked
死了一定也不喜欢被人踢的
he wouldn't like being kicked either though he's dead
只要我多用半分力
If I used a little more strength
你的手就永远不能再拿武器了
your hand would have become crippled
血鹦鹉
The Bloody Parrot
小魔神，小魔神死了…
The little devil is dead...
这个鹦鹉叫小魔神？
This parrot is called the little devil?
是啊
Yes
是你替他取的名字？
You thought up the name?
不，是个女孩子
No, a girl did
她送给我的时候就有了这个名字
The name came along when she gave it to me
她是什么人
Who was she?
我这一辈子都是规规矩矩的
I have always behaved myself
可是我却荒唐过一次
all my life except once;
那一次把我一生的积蓄都花光了
And that cost me my life's savings
可是她给我得到的满足和刺激
But the pleasure and excitement she gave me
是别人连做梦都想不到的
was out of this world
她在什么地方
Where is she?
那只不过是一间妓院
It was only a whore house
哪家妓院
Which one?
鹦鹉楼
The Parrot Brothel
她叫什么名字
What was her name?
血奴
Xue Nu
Xue Nu?
这棺村里装的是死人还是银子
Is a dead body in the coffin or is there silver?
死人也好银子也好
Doesn't matter
这家伙一定是疯子
He's got to be a nut
是嘛，哪有人带着棺村逛窑子的
Indeed... who else'd carry a coffin to a brothel
那疯子上血奴房去了
He's gone up to Xue Nu's room
血奴不会喜欢一个疯子的
She wouldn't like a nutcase
是，这个疯子哪儿比得上严公子强
Indeed, how could he compare with master Yian
红玉姑娘
Miss Hong Yu
奇怪
Strange
你是…
You are...
你不要管我是谁
Never mind who I am
我想问你
I want to ask you
你到这里来是想找哪位姑娘陪你
which lady are you looking for?
血奴
Xue Nu
你这个人真怪，用棺村装银子
You're a strange guy; using a coffin to put your silver
这口棺村里一分银子都没有
There's no silver in the coffin
那是个死人
You mean that's a dead person?
我只知道他是我朋友
All I know is he's my friend;
至于是死是活那并不重要
it doesn't matter whether he's dead or alive
你至少还应该知道一件事
You should at least know one thing
什么事
What?
今天晚上是死人留下还是你留下
Whether you or the dead person will stay behind
有什么区别
What's the difference?
要是活人就得付钱，死人我免誉
If alive, then you'll have to pay, if dead, it's free
这样看起来只有他留下，我出去了
Looks like I'll be the one leaving
那又何必这么急呢
Why so impatient?
如果我不出去
If I don't go out,
我身上有一件东西就要出去了
something on me will
什么东西
What?
你看
Look
夜明珠
Night pearl?
现在你可以留下了
Now you can stay
你为什么在墙上画这些可怕的画
Why have you drawn such horrible pictures on the wall?
我喜欢要人害怕
I like to frighten people
害怕也是一种刺激
Fear is a stimulation
常常能刺激得男人发狂
and drives men crazy
这些妖魔在干什么
What are these devils doing?
在庆贺魔王的寿辰
Celebrating the devil king's birthday
这是魔王
This is the devil king?
是的
Yes
可是今天晚上你就是我的魔王
You are my devil tonight
这只鹦鹉为什么是红的
Why is this parrot red?
他是魔血滴成的
It has been formed by the devil's blood
围绕在他身边的十三只怪物
And the 13 monsters surrounding her
就是他的奴才叫血奴
are her slaves and called Xue Nu
你想做他的奴才
You want to be its slave
所以改名叫血奴，是吗？
hence your name, right?
今天晚上我只想做你的奴才
I only want to be your slave tonight
所有的魔血都滴成这只血鹦鹉
All the devil's blood has been used up to make this
和十三个血奴？
Bloody Parrot & the 13 slaves?
不，另有十三滴血结成了石头
No, another 13 drops of blood made a stone
在一瞬间它就可以夺人魂魄的石头
which could seize one's soul in a wink
这种石头就叫做血石
It's called bloody rock
是不是这种石头？
Is this it?
啊！血石
Bloody rock
我就可以见到魔王
I could see the Devil King
这个女人是我的
This woman is mine
你这个小杂种，给我滚开，给我滚
Bastard, scram
你这个魔鬼到底是谁，说
Who the devil are you? Speak
你这个小杂种，嫖了我的女人
Bastard, you got my woman
我要杀死你，我不会放过你的
I'll kill you
怎么？你没事吧？
Are you okay?
没什么，你真好
I'm fine. Very kind of you indeed
谁？
Who is it?
我没事了，你下去吧
I'm okay, you may leave
她是谁？
Who is she?
是我的乳娘
My wet nurse
现在我才知道
Now I know the stone you gave me
你给我的那块石头是春药
was an aphrodisiac
那你为什么说是魔石
Why did you say it was the devil's stone?
因为魔王和血鹦鹉的故事
Because the story of the devil and the Bloody Parrot
实在把我迷住了
fascinated me
我不喜欢这个故事
I don't like the story,
更不喜欢这幅画
and more so the picture
这画谁画的
Who drew this?
我不知道，听说是涵古斋褛的
I heard Han Gu Studio did that
我要去买白粉把它涂掉
I'll get some white powder and plaster over it
涵古斋的主人死了已有三年
The Han Gu Studio's owner has been dead for 3 years
涵古斋的店门也有三年没打开过
and his shop has not operated since then
你不是想买石灰吗
Do you want to buy lime powder?
趁我没有睡觉你还是可以买得到的
You can still get it before I sleep
你是谁
Who are you?
你怎么知道我要买石灰
How do you know what I want?
大家都叫我老蛔虫
Everyone calls me roundworm
怪不得你像我肚内的蛔虫
It's no wonder then, that
知道我想什么
you know my thoughts inside out
嗯，你要刷墙，要在这儿待下去
You want to plaster the wall and stay here
只可惜你一定待不久的
But you wouldn't stay long as
也许连墙都没干，你已经没命了
you might die before the wall dries
老板，有没有酒？
Boss, some wine?
对不起…
Sorry...
是谁叫你来杀我的？
Who asked you to come and kill me?
是我
I did
你想杀我？
You're after my life?
血奴要做生意
Xue Nu needs to do business
做生意的姑娘不能养小白脸
she can't afford to support a man
你凭什么这样说？
Why do you say this?
血奴从小吃我的奶长大
I brought her up
就该听我的
so she should listen to me
还好我吃奶的时间已经过了
I am past my weaning period
老太婆
Old madam,
你想开一点，别气坏了身子
don't boil with anger
这是你要的石灰
This is the lime powder you want
你也想杀我？
You want to kill me too?
是的
Yes
你也是为了血奴想杀我？
Also because of Xue Nu?
本来就有这个打算
That was my intention
看来你的身手还不错
You seem to have good skills
大概还能在我手上过三招
and could fight with me
啊？
Oh?
可是我还得警告你
But I must warn you
血奴本来就是我的
Xue Nu is mine
她要养小白脸，就得养我
If she supports a man, that should be me
我哪一点不比你强
You are not a better man than me
只有一点，你的鼻子太扁了
Just marginally; your nose is a bit flat
现在看来你可真的变成了小白脸了
Now you really look like a gigolo
完了
I'm finished...
完了？还没完
Not yet
如果我再多赐你一招
If I cut you one more time,
你连做小白脸的资格都没有了
your handsome face will be ruined
滚
Get lost
夭灵灵地灵灵
Summoning the spirits
太上老君急急如令令
Lord Lao Zi of the Great Monad is potent and binding
夭灵灵地灵灵
Summoning the spirits
太上老君急急如令令
Lord Lao Zi of the Great Monad is potent and binding
割他的鼻子挖他的眼
Cut off his nose, gouge his eyes
掏他的五脏挖心肝
and eviscerate him
夭灵灵地灵灵
Summoning the spirits
太上老君急急如令令
Lord Lao Zi of the Great Monad is potent and binding
割他的鼻子挖他的眼
Cut off his nose, gouge his eyes
掏他的五脏挖心肝
and eviscerate him
把他的心掏出来喂狗
Take out his heart to feed the dogs
这个女人是一个巫婆
This woman is a witch
这里的人都很怕她
Even the people here are afraid of her
因为她的诅咒一向都很灵验
Because her curses are efficacious
只不过真正要杀你的人还不是她
It's just that she's not the one who wants to kill you
那是谁？
Who is it then?
李大娘
Madam Li
李大娘为什么要杀我？
Why does Madam Li want to kill me?
我只知道杀人从来不问为什么
I never ask why
你就是长剑高欢？
So you're Gao Huan, the Long Sword?
你还不动手？
Aren't you going to fight?
我不想这里发生更多事情
I don't want anything more to happen here
请你尽快离开平安颌
Please leave the town immediately
你是谁？
Who are you?
为什么用化尸水把尸体化去？
Why are you dissolving the corpse?
我叫安子豪，是这里的颌长
I am An Zhi Hao, the major of this town
因为有一个官职比我大几十倍
Because someone who is much higher in rank than I am
比铁恨更有名气的捕头将会来这里
and more famous than Tie Hen is going to be here soon
他是谁
Who is he?
常笑，常大人
Lord Chang, Chang Xiao
毒剑常笑
Chang Xiao, the Deadly Sword
你是聪明人就应该尽快离开这里
You'd better be smart and leave quickly
谢谢你的忠告
Thanks for your advice
但是有一件事情我不明白
But there's still something which I don't understand
什么事
What is that?
李大娘是什么人？
Who is Madam Li?
她为什么要杀我？
Why does she want to kill me?
她…她是血奴的母亲
She's the mother of Xue Nu
血奴的母亲？为什么要杀我？
Xue Nu
李大娘？
Madam Li?
高欢死了
Guo Huan is dead
传话下去，不杀了叶霆风
Pass on my order that Ye Ting Feng must be killed
不要怪我李大娘不客气
or I'll have to be rude
你奶妈来过了？
Has your nanny been here?
没有，你一走我就睡了
No, I fell asleep after you left
你见过她？
Did you see her?
她想杀我
She's after my life
我到这儿才半天
I've been here for only half a day
这里所有人个个都想杀我
and everyone here wants to kill me
是不是他们之间
Wonder if there are any
都有什么不可告人的秘密？
secrets between them that I am not aware of?
你能不能带我去见一个人？
Could you bring me to meet someone?
谁啊？
Who?
我想见一下李大娘
Madam Li
你真的要见她？
You really want to see her?
你想干什么？
What do you want?
我要挖出你的眼睛
I'll gouge out your eyes;
看你还想不想见她
see if you still want to see her
为什么不让我去见她？
Why don't you let me see her?
她是个魔女
She's a witch
你只要见到她就永远不会再见我了
You'll never see me again when you meet her
我不想你离开我
I don't want you to leave me
有人动过这个棺村吗？
Did someone move this coffin?
没有
No
铁恨，我一定送你回家好好安葬
Tie Hen, I'll give you a proper burial
不要在这里作怪吓唬人
Stop scaring people here
你在跟谁说话
Who are you talking to?
刚才是你在说话吗
Did you say something just now?
不错，是我
That's right, it's me
把棺村打开
Open the coffin
棺村里面是个死人，有什么好看的
What for? There's just a corpse inside
棺村里除了死人之外
Apart from a dead person,
逃犯、土匪、私货、赃物
fugitives, bandits, smuggled goods, booties...
全都可以装进去的
All of that could be stored there
不过…
But...
不过什么？
But what?
开棺之后如果要有什么意外…
If anything should happen after opening the coffin...
有什么意外？
What could happen?
这个人活着的时候很凶
This person used to be very fierce
死了以后变成厉鬼
he could become an evil spirit after death
厉鬼作祟，什么事他都做得出来的
He could do anything
见鬼，开棺搜
Bullshit, open the coffin
是
Yes
这个人究竟是死的还是活的？
Is he dead or alive?
你不会自己模模
Feel him for yourself
你醒一醒，醒醒，血奴
Xue Nu, wake up
你有没有看到我棺村里的朋友？
Did you see my friend inside the coffin?
棺村里的朋友，怎么了？
What about him?
他不见了
He's gone
你看看，脚印…
Look, the footprints...
有血
Blood
"Peace Inn"
他们两个虽不如你的经验老到
Although they are not as experienced as you
也是你们这行中的高手
they are still considered experts even amongst you
无论发现了什么最好不要对我隐瞒
You'd better not hide anything from me
也不要给我铁恨那种报告
Don't give me reports like those of Tie Hen's
滚开，我这里还要做生意
Get lost, I'm doing business here
你们给我滚，滚
Get lost
我不许你们这样做，滚
I won't allow this, get lost
你以后根本不必再做生意了
You cannot do business then
我做鬼也不会放过你的
Not letting you off easily even when I become a ghost
世上如果真有厉鬼报仇
If there were ghosts
我最少已死了一千次
I would have died a thousand times
绝不会活到今天
and wouldn't have survived till now
死因找到了没有
Have you found out the cause of his death?
中毒而死的
He was poisoned
毒药还是暗器？
Poison or secret weapon?
还不知道
Don't know yet
心脏剖开了没有？
Cut up his heart yet?
心脏也要剖验？
His heart too?
要，一定要
Of course
是
Yes
萧老头
Master Xiao
我看你也是验不出什么结果了
I don't think you'd be able to find out anything
膝盖下有几根很小的针
There're some tiny needles in the knees
萧老头
Master Xiao
针是十心堂精制，毒是千机毒
The needles and poison have been made to be deadly
这种毒针就是七星夺命针
This is a Seven Stars Lethal Needle
大人慧眼明察
You're right, sir
红石击中的痕迹与针口部位相同
The wound from the rock is the same as the needle's
看来毒针是镶在红石上的
It seems likely that the needle came with the rock
是
Yes
大人，心脏里找到毒针
A poisonous needle is found in the heart
拿过来
Bring it over
是
Yes
你很聪明
You're clever
当我下令剖开心脏
Guess you knew when I ordered the heart to be cut open
迟早会发现七星夺命针的存在
that I'd find out about The Needle sooner or later;
你才肯说出针口这种事
And hence you had no choice but to confess
可惜你不够狡猾
But you're not sly enough
否则你应该知道
or you would have known that
我是在试探你真正的工作能力
I was testing your ability
铁恨是怎样死的
How did Tie Hen die?
中毒
He was poisoned
什么毒
What poison?
不清楚
Don't know
你的验尸报告我已看过
I've read your report on the autopsy
我知道
I know
有一件事我想你是否知道
There's something which you should know
郭简的尸体我已重新剖验
I've re-examined Guo Kan's body
郭简的死因跟他们都一样
Guo Kan died of the same cause as they did
可是在郭简的身上
But why couldn't you find The Needle
你为什么找不出七星夺命针
in Guo Kan's body
铁恨他有没有死？
Is Tie Hen dead?
铁恨跟你到底想隐瞒些什么
What are Tie Hen and you hiding from me?
你们是不是鹦鹉？血鹦鹉，说
Are you the Bloody Parrot? Speak
你应该知道
You should know
我的手下都是用刑的好手
my men are all good at inflicting torture
你也应该知道
You should also know
像我这把年纪还能活多久
that a man of my age won't live long
只怕你想死也没那么容易
I'm afraid you won't die so easily
你还没有权力控制一个人的生死
You haven't had the power to control one's life yet
我不想你死，你就绝对不能死
You can't die if I wish it to be otherwise
铁恨的棺木在哪里？
Where's Tie Hen's coffin?
这个，在鹦鹉楼
At the Parrot Brothel
听说铁恨的尸体
It's been rumoured that Tie Hen
昨晚变了僵尸，失了踪
has become a vampire last night and disappeared
失踪？
Disappeared?
张铁，林平，你们两个留下
Zhang Tie, Lin Ping, you two stay behind
是
Yes
带路去鹦鹉楼
Show me the way to the Parrot Brothel
你就是血奴？
So you are Xue Nu?
你为什么不把那副棺村搬出去
Why didn't you move that coffin out?
这不是我的东西
This is not mine
是叶霆风不肯搬？
Was it Ye Ting Feng who didn't want to move it?
我没问他，今天我还没有见到他
Didn't ask him... I haven't seen him yet today
听他说他去找那个变了僵尸的朋友
I hear he's gone to look for his vampire friend
说不定他现在已被僵尸指住喉咙
Maybe he's been killed by the vampire
再也回不来了
and won't come back
晚忠 在
- Wan Zhong - Yes
检查棺村
Check the coffin
是
Yes
韩老大在
- Master Hon - Yes
你与安子豪去剖验那两个公差
You & An Zi Hao go check the two officers' bodies
尽快把报告送来
and bring me the report immediately
是
Yes
大人，棺村打开过两次
My lord, the coffin has been opened twice
第二次打开后没钉上
it wasn't nailed secure since then
把它打开
Open it
是
Yes
你就是叶霆风
Are you Ye Ting Feng?
是的
Yes
你知不知道棺村是用来装死人的
Don't you know a coffin is used to carry someone dead?
我知道
I do
那你为什么要睡进去
Then why are you sleeping in there?
我不想这么快就变成死人
I don't want to become a dead man so quickly
啊？有人要杀你？
Oh? Someone wants to kill you?
是的，这里所有人都想杀我
Yes, everyone here is after my life
睡在棺村里也不一定安全
It may not be absolutely safe to sleep in a coffin
很容易被人活活钉死的
You may actually suffocate & die in there
好在这副棺村出过僵尸
It's lucky that a vampire has been here
没有人敢接近它
so nobody dares to come close
僵尸？
Vampire?
大人
My lord,
在死了公差的断臂中
a Seven Stars Lethal Needle was found
剖出了一枚七星夺命针
in the amputated arm of the dead officer
七星夺命针？
The Seven Stars Lethal Needle?
你肯定铁恨死了？
Are you sure Tie Hen is dead?
一个人的死活我还分得出来
I can tell the difference between a living & a dead man
死人居然还会放毒针杀人？
A dead man using poisonous needle to kill?
你不如去问那个死人好了
You'd better go and ask that dead man
这幅魔画有时有鬼眼出现
Demon eyes sometimes appear in the picture
所以你把它涂了？
So you covered it up?
是的
Yes
卜鬲壁是谁住的？
Who's living next door?
采妈妈住的，是一个巫婆
Madam Song, she's a witch
巫婆
Witch?
僵尸？魔画？鬼眼
Vampire? A demonic drawing? Ghost eye?
走，去找那个巫婆
Go, go and find that witch
是
Yes
笨蛋
Idiot
什么人
Who is it?
果然是她在偷窥
She's peeping
你看她拜的是五毒鬼佛
See, she worships devilish idols
看来一定是用毒的能手
She must be an expert in using poison
怪不得那些秽物恶臭到令人昏眩
No wonder those things stink
小心你的手下不要乱碰这里的东西
Ask your men not to touch anything
可能有毒
There could be poison stains
不要打开
Don't open it
唐老大，解药
Master Tong, antidote
住手，不要打了
Stop, stop fighting
你疯了？
Are you crazy?
僵尸
Vampire
尹平…
Wan Ping...
"lmperial Guard"
全到了没有？
All here?
全都到齐了，三爷
All here, Master San
在这里，这里是一千两
Here's a thousand taels of silver
三爷，要我们弟兄来做什么事
What can we do for you?
要你们去抓一个人
To go and catch someone
谁？
Who is it?
血奴
Xue Nu
这很容易，三爷放心，走
That's easy, Master San, don't worry, go
等一等，血奴身边有个贴身的丫环
Wait, Xue Nu has a personal maid
她名字叫红玉，她擅用绣花针杀人
Her name is Hong Yu & her embroidery needle is lethal
你们见了她千万要小心
Be careful of her
最好是避开她
Better avoid seeing her
知道了
Understood
走吧
Go
走
上当了
Tricked
上
Go
快走
Hurry and go
小心
Be careful
你们七个人的面皮
The skin from the seven of you
刚好够我做一条裙子
is just enough for me to make a skirt
上
Attack
你是红玉
You are Hong Yu
布阵
Set the formation
可惜你这个阵
Too bad your formation
顾得上面，顾不了下面
can't cover you from all sides
顾得前面，顾不了后面
There're some weak points
你几时学会把人绣成瞎子
Since when have you learnt to turn someone blind?
三十年前
Thirty years ago
原来你就是江湖上号称娃娃脸的
So you are the famous Doll Face
夺命神针红玉姑娘
Killer Needle Lady Hong Yu
把血奴交给我
Hand Xue Nu over to me
她在我身边会安全得多
She's safer with me
你到鹦鹉楼来干什么
What are you doing here at the Parrot Brothel?
她是我娘派来保护我的
She's been sent by my mother to protect me
把尸体搬走
Move the corpse away
你应该知道这个女人是我的
You should know that this woman is mine
我知道
I know
你为什么要把她带走
Why are you taking her away?
我只是想证明一件事
I just want to prove one thing
什么事
What is that?
滇王府的一件丑事
A scandal at the residence of the Prince of Dian
那跟血奴有什么关系
What has it to do with Xue Nu?
血奴不是李大娘的女儿
Xue Nu isn't the daughter of Madam Li
她是滇王妃的私生女
She's the illegitimate daughter of the Princess of Dian
也是滇王府唯一生存的人
and the only survivor in the family of the Prince Dian
你凭什么这样说
What makes you say that?
二十年前我在滇王府工职画师
20 years ago, I was a painter at the Prince residence
官职虽小
Although I was a humble officer then
但有机会进入王府接近王爷
I had the chance to get close to the Prince
有一天奉召进王府
One day, I was summoned
郭总管，像已经画好了，请过目
Chief Guo, the painting is finished, please have a look
你等一等，请
Wait, please
红蝙蝠原产拢洲
The red bats originated from Long Zhou
垫伏红蕉花洞，性淫
resided at the Cave, and were licentious
这个血石是用十万只红蝙蝠的血
This blood rock was made from the blood of
凝结提炼而成
a hundred thousand red bats
服食以后，不但长生不老
Once taken, not only could one live forever
还可以壮阳固精
one could be sexually potent
王爷淫虐成性，早有所闻
The Prince is known for his lasciviousness
岂知他还有一种丑恶的性变态
He is also perverse in a certain way
就非我所了解
which I do not understand
这就是我一直想不透
I've been trying in vain to figure this out
一年后，王妃产下一个婴儿
A year later the Princess gave birth to a baby
是男是女，没有人知道
No one knew whether it was a boy or a girl
因为出生的当天
because on the day the baby was born
婴孩就被人抱出宫外
someone took the child away
王妃临别解下一块佩玉
But before that, the Princess hung
挂｝在婴儿的身上
a piece ofjade on the baby's body
从此以后
And from then onwards
宫中不见有人提起这个婴孩
no one in the palace ever mentioned about that baby
奇怪的是血奴身上那块佩玉
It's weird that Xue Nu has got that piece ofjade;
就是王妃当年留下的信物
the same piece which the Princess left behind
其实你不应该把这件事告诉我
You shouldn't have told me that
对，或许我不应该在这儿告诉你
That's right, maybe I shouldn't have
是你
It's you
你说的太多了
You talk too much
你怎么把她杀了
Why did you kill her?
这种人死了喂狗，狗都嫌臭
Death is too good for her
有什么可惜的
what's to be ashamed of?
可是我们少了一条线索
Unfortunately we've got one lead less
第一次见面就这么不客气
You're so unfriendly the first time we meet
想见你实在不容易
It's not that easy to meet you
你有什么事
What do you want?
你大概很熟悉这件东西吧
You might be familiar with this thing
这是血奴身上的佩玉
It's Xue Nu's jade; also a token
也是滇王妃给她私生女的信物
from the Princess to her illegitimate daughter
什么意思
What do you mean?
我还想知道你到底是什么人
I want to know who you are
即使你知道了又怎么样
What if you knew?
我还想娶你
I still want to marry you
你杀了这么多人就是为了这件事
You've killed so many people just for this
有一件事你还不太清楚
There's one thing which you still don't know yet
在我眼里你虽然很迷人
Undeniably I find you very attractive
但是跟滇王府的珠宝比起来
But as compared to the treasures of the Prince of Dian
那批珠宝会更可爱
they are more attractive
有件事你也不太清楚
There's one thing which you still don't know yet
我既不知道什么珠宝
I don't know what treasures you are talking about
也跟滇王府没有丝毫的关系
and I have nothing to do with the Prince of Dian
不要把门关得太早
Don't close your back door too early
你女儿还在我的手里
Your daughter is still in my hands
你是要滇王府的珠宝呢
Do you want to keep the treasures
还是要你的女儿
or your daughter?
这支毒镖三个时辰内就能致人死命
This poisonous dart will kill people in about six hours
这个人质帮不了你
This hostage of yours won't help you much
好狠毒的女人
What a vicious woman you are!
血奴
Xue Nu
想不到我娘这么狠毒
I don't believe that my mother is so vicious
啊，珠宝
Treasures
那不是王府失窃的珠宝吗
Aren't they the lost treasures of the Prince residence?
走
Go
那里有通路
There's a way over there
血奴…
Xue Nu
原来在江湖上兴妖作怪的血鹦鹉
So you are the Bloody Parrot
就是你这条老蛔虫
who has been causing a lot of trouble
其实根本没有什么血鹦鹉
In reality, there's no such thing as the Bloody Parrot
那只是一盏会发光的灯
It's only an illuminated lamp
你们到底在搞什么花样？
What tricks are you playing?
也许你就是赔了这条命
Maybe you would never know
也不会弄清楚
even if you lost your life
好死不如赖活着
In all respects it's to be alive than dead
你偏偏找这个地方来送死
You are digging your own grave
你是…
You are...
当我踏足江湖时
When I got involved in the martial arts world
早就把生死置之度外
I no longer had any regard for my own life
可是我不明白，血奴跟你什么关系
But I still don't get it what Xue Nu has to do with you
血鹦鹉到底是怎么回事
What's the Bloody Parrot all about?
江湖上不怕死的人不多
There aren't many people who are not afraid of death
今天我叫你死个明明白白
I'll give you a good reason to die today
你就是…
So you are...
我就是滇王府的王妃
I am the Princess of Dian
他就是滇王府的总管郭繁
He's Chief Guo Fan
原来你们都还活着
So you are still alive
我们本来都没有死
We have not been dead
只是利用血鹦鹉的传说
We've been using the rumours about the Bloody Parrot
我们伪造了一个
to make up a story
王府珠宝失踪的故事
about the lost treasure
其实谁也没有见过血鹦鹉
No one has ever seen the Bloody Parrot
所有的事都是我们两人安排的
These have just been set up by the two of us
这把剑装有弹簧根本杀不死人
This sword has a spring and cannot kill people
原来你们这样做
You did this
就是为了吞占这批
just to grab all for yourselves
要朝贡当今天子的珠宝
these treasures meant as tribute to the Emperor
你说吞占也好、冒犯朝廷也好
You can put it in whatever way you like
只是我太喜爱这批珠宝了
I just love these treasures so much
可惜你们白白的送掉了王爷的性命
But you've made the Prince lose his life for nothing
人总是要死的
Death comes to us all
况且他只是一个荒淫无能的老人
Besides, he was a licentious old man
天下最毒女人心，果然如此
No wonder it's said that women are vicious
无毒不丈失，那又怎么说
It's also said men are vicious
你以为可以安享这批珠宝了吗？
Can you be at peace with these treasures?
天下两大名捕
The two famous constables
常笑，铁恨都已经死了
Chang Xiao and Tie Hen are dead
那我还担心什么？
What have I got to worry about?
铁手无情铁恨他并没有死
Tie Hen is not dead
你应该知道他早就变成僵尸了
You should know that he's turned into a vampire
你以为僵尸可怕吗？
Do you think a vampire is terrifying?
僵尸并不可怕
No
可怕的是你并没有把我杀死
The most terrible thing is you failed to kill me
这块所谓夺人魂魄的血石
This so-called blood rock supposed to suck one's soul
只不过是一件藏有毒针的暗器
is a secret weapon with poisonous needles
对我来说早已不起作用
I am immune to it
当鹦鹉楼出现僵尸的时候
When a vampire appeared at the Parrot Brothel
我早就应该想到
I should have known that
你是用窒息功来装死
you faked your death
可惜你的脑子一向不够敏捷
But you are not smart enough
只要你放出我的朋友，跟我归案
Had you released my friend and gone back with me
也许可以保全你们的性命
you might have saved your own life
谢谢我…
Thanks to me...
难道是你救了我？
Did you save me?
他只不过是一只鹦鹉
It's nothing but a parrot
血奴，是你
Xue Nu, it's you